<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
    "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY date "September 2009"> 
  <!ENTITY version "">
  <!ENTITY application ""> 
]>
<article id="index" lang="en">

  <!-- Header -->
  <articleinfo>
    <title>Imagination DVD Slide Show Creator</title>
    <pubdate>&date;</pubdate>
    <copyright>
      <year>2009</year>
      <holder>Giuseppe Torelli</holder>
    </copyright>
    <legalnotice id="legalnotice">
      <para>
        Permission is granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document
        under the terms of the GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.1 or
        any later version published by the Free Software Foundation; with no
        Invariant Sections, with no Front-Cover Texts, and with no Back-Cover
        Texts. The complete license text is available from the <ulink
        type="http" url="http://www.gnu.org/">Free Software Foundation</ulink>.
      </para>
    </legalnotice>

    <authorgroup>
      <author>
        <firstname>Giuseppe</firstname>
        <surname>Torelli</surname>
      </author>
	        <author>
        <firstname>Tadej</firstname>
        <surname>Borovšak</surname>
      </author>
    </authorgroup>

    <releaseinfo>
      This manual describes version &version; of &application;.
    </releaseinfo>
  </articleinfo>

  <sect1 id="intro">
    <title>Introduction to &application;</title>

    <para>
      Imagination is a lightweight DVD slide show creator developed in C with the GTK+2 toolkit and Cairo. Imagination is designed to be
      be fast and easy-to-use. Its user interface is clean and intuitive, and does not include any confusing or useless options by default.
	  It requires the ffmpeg encoder to produce the movie file and libsox to handle the audio. Yes you don't need any other third-party software!
    </para>

  <!--  <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>Create folders and documents.</listitem>
      <listitem>Display your files and folders.</listitem>
      <listitem>Manage your files and folders.</listitem>
      <listitem>Run and manage custom actions.</listitem>
      <listitem>Access Removable Media.</listitem>
    </itemizedlist>-->
  </sect1>


   <sect1 id="working-with-files-and-folders">
    <title>Working with Files and Folders</title>


    <sect2 id="opening-files">
      <title>Opening Files</title>

      <para>
        When you open a file, the file manager performs the default action for that file type. For example, opening a text file
        will display it in the default text editor, while opening an image file will display the image in the default image
        viewer.
      </para>

      <para>
        The file manager checks the extension of a file to determine the type of a file. If the file has no known extension, the
        file manager examines the contents of the file.
      </para>

      <sect3 id="executing-the-default-action">
        <title>Executing the Default Action</title>

        <para>
          To execute the default for a file, double-click on the file. For example, the default action for audio files is to
          play the it with the default music playing application. In this case, you can double-click on the file to open the
          file in the music player.
        </para>

        <para>
          You can set <application>Thunar</application> preferences so that you click once on a file to execute the default
          action. For information, see <xref linkend="preferences-behavior" />.
        </para>
      </sect3>

      <sect3 id="executing-non-default-actions">
        <title>Executing Non-Default Actions</title>

        <para>
          To execute actions other than the default action for a file, select the file that you want to perform an action on.
          Choose the desired action from the <emphasis>Open With</emphasis> choices available in <guimenu>File</guimenu> menu
          or an <guimenu>Open With</guimenu> submenu.
        </para>
      </sect3>

      <sect3 id="adding-actions">
        <title>Adding Actions</title>

        <para>
          To add actions associated with a file type, perform the following steps:
        </para>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              In the main area, select a file of the type to which you want to add an action.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Choose <menuchoice><guimenu>File</guimenu><guimenuitem>Open With Other Application...</guimenuitem></menuchoice>
              from the main menu.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Either choose an application in the <guilabel>Open With</guilabel> dialog or select <guibutton>Use a custom command</guibutton>
              and browse to the program with which you wish to open this type.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>

        <para>
          The action you have chosen is now added to the list of actions for that particular file type. If you enabled the
          <guibutton>Use as default for this kind of file</guibutton> option or there was no prior action associated with the
          type, the newly added action is the default.
        </para>

        <para>
          You may also add actions using the <guibutton>Open With</guibutton> button under
          <menuchoice><guimenu>File</guimenu><guimenuitem>Properties...</guimenuitem></menuchoice>.
        </para>
      </sect3>

      <sect3 id="modifiying-actions">
        <title>Modifying Actions</title>

        <para>
          To modify the actions associated with a file or file type, perform the following steps:
        </para>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              In the main area, select a file of the type for which you want to modify the action.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Choose <menuchoice><guimenu>File</guimenu><guimenuitem>Properties...</guimenuitem></menuchoice> from the main menu.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Select the new default action using the <guilabel>Open With</guilabel> button or add a new action by choosing
              <guimenuitem>Open With Other Application...</guimenuitem> from the drop down menu.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>

        <para>
          To remove a previously added action for a file type, bring up the <guilabel>Open With</guilabel> dialog as described
          above, right-click the action you want to remove and choose <guimenuitem>Remove Launcher</guimenuitem>.
        </para>
      </sect3>
    </sect2>


    <sect2 id="file-properties">
      <title>File Properties</title>

      <para>
        The file properties window shows more information about any file or folder in the file manager. With this window, you can also
        do the following:
      </para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Change the icon for special files, such as application launchers and URL links.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Add or remove emblems for a file or folder.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Change the UNIX file permissions for a file or folder.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Choose which application is used to open a file and other files of the same type.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/file-properties.png" format="PNG"/>
          </imageobject>

          <textobject>
            <phrase>File Properties</phrase>
          </textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>

      <para>
        To open the file properties window, perform the following steps:
      </para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Select the file or folder whose properties you want to examine or change. You cannot
            select multiple items at once and display the properties that are in common to all
            items currently.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Do one of the following:
            <itemizedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Choose <menuchoice><guimenu>File</guimenu><guimenuitem>Properties...</guimenuitem></menuchoice> from the main menu.</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>Right-click the selected item and choose <guimenuitem>Properties...</guimenuitem> from the context menu.</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>Press <keycombo><keycap>Alt</keycap><keycap>Return</keycap></keycombo>.</para>
              </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>
</article>
<!--
	vim:set ts=2 sw=2 et ai encoding=UTF-8:
-->
